<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Jairam's Blog</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Jairam's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GoodPlates</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/good-plates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/good-plates/</guid><description>Good Plates is a minimalist recipe website that removes choice paralysis by showing a single recipe at a time to users based on their preferences.
The frontend is written in Typescript and hosted on Netlify. The backend leverages API Gateway and AWS Lambda for routing requests. The recipes are stored in DynamoDB using a custom B-Tree implementation.
Link to site</description></item><item><title>Shelltube</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/shelltube/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/shelltube/</guid><description>Shelltube is a Youtube client for Powershell. No login or authentication is required. Just type what you want to listen to and Shelltube will play it for you.
Link to repository</description></item><item><title>Notecard</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/notecard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/notecard/</guid><description>Convert your notes into flashcards. Enter your notes manually or copy/paste them into the text box field. Flashcards will be created for lines containing a dash &amp;rsquo; - &amp;lsquo;. The left half will be the term and the right half is the definition.
Link to service</description></item><item><title>Concord</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/concord/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/concord/</guid><description>Concord is a service used to stream your music that you have stored on SkyDrive.
Link to service</description></item><item><title>Shellit</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/shellit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/shellit/</guid><description>Shellit is a Reddit client for PowerShell. Simply run it without any parameters and you will be prompted to login (optional).
Link to repository</description></item><item><title>Chauffeur</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/chauffeur/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/chauffeur/</guid><description>Chauffeur is an Android app that allows users to add multiple addresses to their route. Chauffeur will then optimize the route to minimize the amount of time spent driving. Users are then be navigated through their route via Google Navigation. You can import addresses from your Google Calendar, Google Contacts, CSV files. This app is an implementation of the Travelling Salesman problem (TSP).
Edit: This app is no longer on the Google Play Store</description></item><item><title>Element Converter</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/element-converter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/element-converter/</guid><description>Element Converter is an Android app that allows you to convert from grams, moles, or atoms, into both of the other two. For example: you can choose 2 moles of Oxygen. After pressing convert, you will have 2 moles of Oxygen converted in grams and atoms.
Edit: This app is no longer on the Google Play Store</description></item></channel></rss>