<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jairam's Blog</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Jairam's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jairampatel.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How do you find your top 3 favorite Disney movies?</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/2022/04/19/how-do-you-find-your-top-3-favorite-disney-movies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/2022/04/19/how-do-you-find-your-top-3-favorite-disney-movies/</guid><description>What is the problem? How would you find your top 3 favorite Disney movies? Even if you were to consider just the movies from the last 10 years, that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of movies to consider (an even 100 as of writing this post).
If this question were asked in a programming environment, we would probably use quick-sort easy-peasy since it’s pretty fast with an average runtime of \(\mathcal{O}(n\log{}n)\). However, if this were asked in a human environment (strange, I know), quick sort may not be the best since the worst case number of comparisons is \(\mathcal{O}(n^2)\).</description></item><item><title>GoodPlates</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/good-plates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/good-plates/</guid><description>Good Plates is a minimalist recipe website that removes choice paralysis by showing a single recipe at a time to users based on their preferences.
The frontend is written in Typescript and hosted on Netlify. The backend leverages API Gateway and AWS Lambda for routing requests. The recipes are stored in a custom B-Tree implementation on top of DynamoDB.
Link to site</description></item><item><title>Play Along</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/play-along/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/play-along/</guid><description>Link to extension
Play Along is a small, compact Chrome extension that is activated when you listen to music on YouTube. Once the YouTube video is loaded, Play Along will search Ultimate Guitar for the corresponding chords and tabs. If no match is found, clicking on the &amp;ldquo;Chords&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Tabs&amp;rdquo; buttons will open up the search page in Ultimate Guitar.
In addition to Ultimate Guitar, users also have the option of navigating to the Chordify page.</description></item><item><title>Rebound</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/rebound/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/rebound/</guid><description>Link to download
Rebound is a game with multi-colored balls bouncing around. By playing this game, you will improve your ability to multi-task and focus on multiple things at once.
How to play All balls will have a number on them. When balls bounce against the wall, that number will decrease. When the ball value has gone down to one, you must press on one of the four wall quadrants to let the ball through.</description></item><item><title>Shelltube a Youtube client for Powershell</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/2014/11/27/shelltube-a-youtube-client-for-powershell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/2014/11/27/shelltube-a-youtube-client-for-powershell/</guid><description>Download Shelltube here
With the addition of this post, 67% of my blog posts will have been about Powershell. I should probably diversify my projects a bit.
Shelltube is a Youtube client for Powershell. Just type what video you want to listen/watch and Shelltube will play it for you.
How it works
In version 1.0, Shelltube will launch Internet Explorer (sorry, it was the common denominator among Windows users). Although the default setting is to display the window, the user will have the option of hiding the Internet Explorer window.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Shellit a Reddit client for Powershell</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/2013/06/30/introducing-shellit-a-reddit-client-for-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/2013/06/30/introducing-shellit-a-reddit-client-for-powershell/</guid><description>A few weeks ago, I had the idea of making a Reddit client for PowerShell. One of the reasons for making Shellit was you can browse Reddit and look like you’re working that I hadn’t done much scripting in PowerShell before. Plus it gave me a chance to finally start making my own repositories on Github.
Shellit is extremely primitive. Currently, users can:
Login if they want to Navigate through different pages of reddit Open links in the PowerShell window View comments on self posts Some of the improvements I’ll probably make in my next update will be to:</description></item><item><title>Installing Arch Linux on My Cr 48</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/2013/04/17/installing-arch-linux-on-my-cr-48/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/2013/04/17/installing-arch-linux-on-my-cr-48/</guid><description>CR-48 is the beta Chromebook released by Google several years ago. It was given away for free to those who applied/were selected. I consider myself extremely fortunate for having been selected and I tried to make the most of it.
If you’re not aware, Chromebooks run on Chrome OS, which is essentially just the Chrome browser. It is built upon a Linux kernel so if you were to flip the hardware switch to developer mode (as I did multiple times), you would be able to use the shell and gain more control over your Chromebook.</description></item><item><title>Shelltube</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/shelltube/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/shelltube/</guid><description>Shelltube is a Youtube client for Powershell. No login or authentication is required. Just type what you want to listen to and Shelltube will play it for you.
Link to repository</description></item><item><title>Notecard</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/notecard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/notecard/</guid><description>Convert your notes into flashcards. Enter your notes manually or copy/paste them into the text box field. Flashcards will be created for lines containing a dash &amp;rsquo; - &amp;lsquo;. The left half will be the term and the right half is the definition.
Link to service</description></item><item><title>Concord</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/concord/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/concord/</guid><description>Concord is a service used to stream your music that you have stored on SkyDrive.
Link to service</description></item><item><title>Shellit</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/shellit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/shellit/</guid><description>Shellit is a Reddit client for PowerShell. Simply run it without any parameters and you will be prompted to login (optional).
Link to repository</description></item><item><title>Chauffeur</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/chauffeur/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/chauffeur/</guid><description>Chauffeur is an Android app that allows users to add multiple addresses to their route. Chauffeur will then optimize the route to minimize the amount of time spent driving. Users are then be navigated through their route via Google Navigation. You can import addresses from your Google Calendar, Google Contacts, CSV files. This app is an implementation of the Travelling Salesman problem (TSP).
Edit: This app is no longer on the Google Play Store</description></item><item><title>Element Converter</title><link>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/element-converter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jairampatel.github.io/projects/element-converter/</guid><description>Element Converter is an Android app that allows you to convert from grams, moles, or atoms, into both of the other two. For example: you can choose 2 moles of Oxygen. After pressing convert, you will have 2 moles of Oxygen converted in grams and atoms.
Edit: This app is no longer on the Google Play Store</description></item></channel></rss>